You must not watch this.
I'm warning you.
You can never unsee it.
But if you do watch...
.. Gagan Rassmussen. I'm Gagan Rassmussen.
This is Le Verrier lab
in orbit around Neptune.
EERIE GROANING
I've put things together
into some kind of order
so that you can understand,
so you can have some idea.
There are bits missing. Sorry about that.
I don't fully understand
what's been going on here.
But, er...
This is what happened.
ROARING
Stop staring!
'They came from Triton.
'This is Chopra.
'Bit of an attitude, in my opinion.'
Calm down, pet!
Well, it's ridiculous!
That thing's meant to be
a lethal fighting machine
and it just moons around
like a love-sick puppy!
I could hear you ranting
- from inside the pod, Chopra, for the Gods' sake!
- Feel better?
'Commander Nagata.
'Young, for the responsibility.
'Quite a baptism of fire, I'm afraid.'
Marvellous, ma'am. All hail, Morpheus, eh?
'Deep-Ando. Conscript.
'Likes to think of himself as
the joker of this little group.
'Well... he DID...'
Morpheus, Morpheus, Morpheus...
Sleep's the one thing left to us.
The one thing they couldn't
get their filthy mitts on.
Now, they're even grabbing
that! Colonising it.
- Spoken like a true Rip!
- Don't call me that.
- "Don't call me that, ma'am." Give it a rest, pet.
- Give what a rest?
This is a mission, Chopra. We find
out what's happened on Le Verrier
and then we all go home. Keep
your politics to yourself, OK?
I know someone who'd love to get Chopra
- back home to Triton, eh?
- Ho-ho!
'This one's obvious from
the markings, isn't it?
'We all know a Grunt when we see one.'
Come on. Behave.
Nearly there, kiddies.
'These are the rescue crew.
'Don't get too attached.
'Everything you're about to see is
from their individual viewpoints
'or taken from the station itself
-- the only footage available.'
They came to find me.
This is my station.
My lab.
'I've pieced together the
rescue as best I could.
'If you're going to watch,
then... pay close attention.
'Your lives may depend on it.'
Emergency lighting only.
Grav and orbit's stable.
There must be power.
EERIE GROANING
Nothing?
No sign of anyone.
There was no crew.
No crew left.
They did find others, though.
Strangers.
What the hell happened here?
- Hide seek.
- Maybe they play hide seek.
Hide AND seek! Why do they miss
out words? It's infuriating!
Chopra, don't be anger.
"Don't be an-gry!"
Is it so hard to breed
them to speak properly?
Oh, lighten up!
- What now?
- Talk.
- What?
- People talk.
CLARA: Do you ever get the
feeling like you're being watched?
THE DOCTOR: Paranoia!
- Why is it so dark?
- Night-time setting.
Faulty filament. Three-day week.
- So, orbit around Neptune?
- Yeah. This close into the planet,
they must have some pretty powerful
anti-grav shielding on board.
Looks like a Japanese restaurant.
Oh! Have you brought me
to a space restaurant!?
- People never do that, you know?
- Do what?
They never put the word
"space" in front of something
just because everything's all
sort of hi-tech and future-y.
It's never "space restaurant"
or "space champagne"
or "space"... you know..."hat".
It's just "restaurant",
"champagne" or "hat".
Even if this was a restaurant...
- What about spacesuit?
- Pedant!
WEAPONS POWERING UP
- Hello!
- You crew?
Are you crew?
"Engineering stress assessors"?
Yes, yes, we are.
- We're here to, er...
- We're here to, er... to, er...
BOTH: .. assess stress...
- So, what happened?
- From the beginning of time?
- That's a very long story.
- (Doctor...!)
Well, we just arrived, you know,
and there was nobody about.
Well, what are you doing here?
24 hours ago, this station fell silent.
No comm signal. Nothing. Dead.
We've come to find out why.
Theories?
Could be anything. Meteorite strike.
Space pirates...
Ah, see? Not just
"pirates". "SPACE pirates"!
- So, what, you are a rescue mission?
- Yes.
- Of four?
- Cuts, pet.
Right. You're to consider yourself...
♪ Part of the furniture! ♪
.. under my command.
- OK. Really?
- Yes, really.
Come on.
We still don't know where we are.
Indo-Japanese.
38th century.
- Tuesday.
- 38th century?
After the Great Catastrophe,
there was a tectonic realignment.
India and Japan, they were...
.. sort of merged.
We still don't know where the
rest of the crew are, though.
I mean, a place this size...
Hey, what? "Great Catastrophe"?
What Great Catastrophe?!
Well... You've got all that to
look forward to, haven't you?
Mind you,
this place looks as if it's
been dead for a long while now.
What is it?
I still can't shake the feeling.
Eyes. Watch.
Eyes in sky.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
Chopra not worry. 474 protect Chopra.
Chopra pretty.
Oh, for the Gods'...
Just back off!
- SCUFFLING
- Oh, come on now...
- Let him go, pet!
- 474 sorry!
- Let him go, now!
- Not help it!
SHE WHIMPERS
It could have killed me!
That's how they're grown. You know
that. They react to any attack.
"Grown"?! They might not
give them much upstairs,
but our friend here
certainly knows how to fight.
You'd be glad of her in
a tight corner, I'll bet.
What does she mean "grown"?
She's a Grunt, Clara.
They're bred in hatcheries.
Cloned muscles.
Low intelligence.
Brute force. Instant army.
That's disgusting!
Well, that's how they
roll in the 38th century...
BOOMING GROWL
GUTTURAL MOANING
(Hold my hand.)
I'm OK.
I'm not.
BOOMING GROWL
- GUNSHOTS - Oh, run,
run, run! - Run! Run!
DEEP-ANDO: Follow me!
Straight ahead.
NO! This way!
Deep-Ando!
Come on!
Quick! Push anything in front of
it! We've got to keep them out!
Deep-Ando! We've lost him!
What the hell are they?
- Not pirates.
- We've got to get Deep-Ando!
Where's your friend?
- Deep-Ando? I dunno. He's...
- He's still out there!
ALL PANT, ROARING
474!
474 YELLS
PATTERING
ROARING AND RUMBLING FADES
ALL GASP
GASPING AND PANTING
What the hell are they?
Where did they go?
'Chief Nagata, this is
Deep-Ando. Where did you go?
BEEPING
HEARBEATS, PANTING
'Nagata, this is Deep-Ando! May the
Gods look favourably upon you!'
May the Gods... Are you there?
Deep-Ando, this is Nagata.
May the Gods look favourably upon you.
Deep-Ando, are you there?
What are you doing?
Finding out what they're made of.
Deep-Ando, are you there?
- Send the Grunt!
- No.
Why not? That's what it's for.
Look, he's still out there!
You can't just abandon him.
I need proper intel before I
risk anyone else. Including 474.
Keep trying the comms.
Deep-Ando, may the Gods
look favourably upon you.
- Well?
- Organic. Definitely organic.
Blood cells. Skin cells. Mucus.
474: Deep-Ando, may the Gods look
favourably upon you. Deep-Ando...
- What are these?
- "Morpheus"? - Morpheus?
Named after the God of Dreams?
Oh, yeah... Ooh, yeah! Not just this.
- So, what are they, then? Sleep pods?
- More than that.
STATIC CRACKLES
- Deep-Ando? Deep-Ando, can you hear me?
- Keep trying.
I could take a look at that, you
know. Triangulate the signal.
- Help you find your friend.
- First, tell me what those things are.
- Deep... Deep-Ando?
- FAINTLY: 'This is Deep...'
Deep-Ando, this is Chopra.
.. I'm getting a signal!
Deep-Ando can you hear me?
Deep-Ando? Deep-Ando, this is Chopra.
[STATIC CRACKLES]
Can you hear me?
- ALARM BLARES
- Doctor! - Clara?
♪ Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom
♪ Mr Sandman, bring me your dreams... ♪
- Clara!
- It's fine, it's just Morpheus.
♪ Make him the cutest
that I've ever seen... ♪
What did you think you were doing?!
Huh?
It dragged me in!
- The wires, they were like snakes,
like it was alive! - Are you OK?
Yeah. It just kind of flicked
over my eyes. Did I sleep?
- Yeah, you did.
- Why did it just grab at me?
Semi-sentient. It thinks it
knows what's good for you.
You obviously needed 40 winks.
Clever little sleep pod.
You said it was something
more than that, though.
- Come on, everyone knows.
- Well, let's just say,
for the sake of argument, that
we don't. What is Morpheus?
Last pod.
This pod.
Not empty.
♪ Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom... ♪
Oh, no. No, no. enough of that.
It's almost like...
someone's...
Careful!
Here. Let me try.
PULSATING BUZZ
SHE TAPS
Hello-o?
It's OK. We're not going to hurt you.
Will you open up now?
Come on. Let's start with names, shall we?
Um, I'm Clara.
This is the Doctor.
- BUZZING STOPS
- It's OK.
'Ah, this is where I come in.'
Hello.
I wanted to get out of there.
Immediately. Of course I did.
But this man... the Doctor...
.. he wanted explanations first.
So...
May the Gods look favourably upon us all!
Friends. We live in a time
of unparalleled prosperity.
A golden age of peace,
harmony and industry...
But every shift must come to an
end. Every working day must stop.
Of course, we can take
stimulants to make that deadline,
to keep us propped up through
that important meeting.
But always, always,
sleep claims us in the end.
Until now!
Sleep-deprivation pods?
Not exactly.
Welcome, Morpheus.
♪ Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom... ♪
The Morpheus machine concentrates
the whole nocturnal experience
into one five-minute burst.
Now, you can go a whole
month without sleep!
- A month?
- All the chemical benefits of rest,
but freeing up the nights to
continue working, working, working!
To get the edge on your competitor.
To turn that extra profit.
That's insane. That's HORRIBLE!
Finally, someone who
sees it for what it is!
Leave the Rip Van Winkles behind
and become one of the new
generation of Wide-Awakes!
The future is here.
The future is now.
Let yourself slip into...
the arms of Morpheus!
- But sleep is...
- Terms and conditions apply.
Sleep is vital. Sleep is
wonderful. Even I sleep.
When?!
Well, when you're not looking.
Morpheus is mine. My invention.
It's changed Triton society forever.
So, how does it work?
The pod sends out a
coded electronic signal
that acts on certain parts of the brain.
Changes the fundamental chemistry.
It's disgusting!
Making people into bloody drones!
- I've said it before...
- Aye. You have.
Colonising our sleep! Is nothing sacred?
We spend a third of our lives
asleep. And time is money.
He's right, man! It's amazing.
Everyone on Triton's using it.
Are they now?
"Sleep, that knits up the
ravelled sleeve of care.
"The death of each day's life,
"sore labour's bath.
"Balm of hurt minds,
"chief nourisher in life's great feast."
Congratulations, Professor!
You've revolutionised the labour market!
- You've conquered nature!
- Thank you.
You've also created an abomination.
The Doctor said that we had
to find the other soldier.
And to find answers.
So, we left the lab.
He thought that there was
some connection between
my Morpheus process and those
creatures that attacked us.
Anyway, you'll see. He...
He had a theory.
- "Sleep dust"?! - Sleep
dust. - You're kidding!
Do I look like I'm kidding?
Is this a kidding face? Ask the crew
of this station if they're kidding.
Or what's left of them.
- But sleep dust?
- Yes. The stuff in the corner of your eye.
The stuff you wipe away every
morning when you wake up.
That's ridiculous. This
is getting us nowhere.
OK, how, Doctor, how can those
things be made of "sleep dust"?
Well, when we sleep, the mucus
crust builds up in our eyes.
Blood cells. Skin cells. That's
what dust largely is. Human skin.
But your meddling has
evolved it. Hot-housed it.
What used to be sleep in your eye
has turned into a carnivorous life form!
You can't just throw
accusations like that around!
So, the longer you're in Morpheus,
the more the dust builds up?
That's slander!
Lying there in those pods, people
are a ready-made food source.
Where are they, then?
Where's the crew?
Digested.
Come on, we need to find Deep-Ando.
Come on.
Oh, come on.
Must be an exit here somewhere.
[HE PANTS]
Listen to me.
Those things. They're everywhere.
For the Gods' sake, come and get me.
ROARING
What about us? We've all
used the pods back on Triton.
- Not all of us.
- This isn't a good time to be smug, pet.
My guess is that the ones you're
using are pretty primitive
compared to what's going on up here.
These are a sort of a Mark II, yeah?
Obviously, I have tried
to improve the process.
Speed things up.
You've succeeded there.
But how does the dust
become those creatures?
You saw what happened.
The dust conglomerates. It moulds
itself into a humanoid form.
It's adaptable. It's clever.
BOOMING MOAN
WEAPONS POWER UP
And it's coming for us.
Look, you came to rescue the
crew. I'm crew. So, rescue me!
How come you're the only one left?
Because I hid.
I hid in the only place I thought
those monsters wouldn't find me.
Look, we've got to get out of here!
No. We can't leave this place until
there's not a trace of the dust
or your machines left.
Or that's it for your lot.
Our lot? What do you mean?
Oh, the human race.
COMPUTER: 'Hey.'
Haruka Deep-Ando, 6897. Let me in.
'I'd love to.'
Well, do it then! My ID must
be on the Corporation index.
'You have to do the song.'
What?!
'You have to do the song, Deep-Ando 6897.'
I haven't got time for this!
'Do the song, please.'
What the hell are you talking about?
'After the Maha
Shivaratri/Oshogasu/Christmas party
'some of the crew reprogrammed me.'
They did, did they?
'Yes. In order to enter rooms,
everyone must do the song.
'It's very amusing.'
But you know who I am! You
just called me by my name.
- 'Nevertheless...'
- HE SIGHS EXASPERATEDLY
What song?
'You know the one.'
I don't!
'Now you're just being
silly. Of course you do!
'Silly Deep-Ando 6897.
'You must know the song.
'Everyone here knows it.'
EERIE GROANING
I'm not from this station.
I'm on a rescue mission.
♪ Bom bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom... ♪
Morpheus?
'The Morpheus song!'
This is insane!
'The song, please.'
Morpheus?
♪ Mr Sandman Bring me your dreams
♪ Make it the cutest... ♪
Haruka Deep-Ando 6897. Let me in!!
'More, please.'
♪ Give him two lips Like roses in... ♪
Please! Let me in! Let me in!
Let me in!
ROARING
HE BREATHES HEAVILY
CREATURE ROARS
He was the first of them to die.
We heard the scream but...
Well, we...
We had our own problems.
RUMBLING
- What's happening?!
- Engines?
No! It's the gravity
shields! They're failing!
Nagata! That thing! The
schematic! Give it to me!
- Who the hell do you think you are?
- Me? I'm in charge!
- You have no authority...
- No. But I'm in charge.
I can bypass the main systems
and reboot the grav-shields!
Listen to him, for God's sake!
He knows what he's talking about!
Doctor!
Doctor, if the grav-shields
are decaying...
Don't say it. Please don't say it!
We're being pulled towards Neptune!
Oh, Gods! Oh, Gods! Oh, Gods!
Hang on!
Argh, this day couldn't get any worse!
CREATURE ROARS
I can do this! I can fix this!
HE WHIMPERS
No! Please! Aaargh!
CREATURE ROARS
No! No!
ALL PANT
The G-force is increasing the closer
we get to the planet! Hold on!
We're back online! Grav-shields
fixed! We're rising!
Go, let's go! Get out of here!
Go, go! Out of here, come on!
Chopra! 474! Come on!
Keep going, move it, move it, move it!
Nagata!
No, I can't leave them!
Chopra! 474! May the
Gods... Where are you?!
WEAPONS POWERING UP
Oh, God. Of all the places! A cold store.
Nagata, are you OK?
No, I'm not.
- What about the others? - I don't
know. - We have to go after them!
- Don't be ridiculous.
- Doctor!
They're under my command!
I owe it to them.
To die? They wouldn't thank you for that.
Nor you, Clara.
"To die, to die.
"Glamis hath murdered sleep,
"therefore Cawdor shall sleep no more.
"Macbeth shall sleep no more."
What?
Shakespeare.
He really knew his stuff.
They all did. The Ancients. The poets.
All those sad songs. All those lullabies.
Sleep is essential to every
sentient being in the universe.
But to humans -- greedy,
filthy, stupid humans...
.. it's an inconvenience
to be bartered away!
Well, now we know the truth.
Sleep isn't just a function. It's blessed.
Every night we dive
deep into that inky pool.
Deep into the arms of Morpheus.
Every morning, we wake up and
wipe the sleep from our eyes.
And that keeps us safe.
Safe from the monsters inside.
Well, the bloody monsters are
outside now. What do we do?!
CLANKING AND THUDDING
Dead meat.
Dear Gods, what are we going to do?
Get ship. Go home.
We can't let those things off here!
If they were to get out, to
spread... It's like an infection.
You don't understand, do you?
Sleepmen bad.
Kill sleepmen.
Yeah. That about sums it up.
Chief Nagata, this is Chopra.
May the Gods look favourably upon you.
STATIC CRACKLES
Chief Nagata, this is Chopra. May the...
We'll head for the rescue ship.
If we don't hear from them soon,
I'm going to have to assume they're dead.
Then what Chopra do?
I have no choice.
I'll have to destroy this whole station.
- What are you doing?
- I've hacked into your helmet cams.
- What?
- Reviewing the footage.
- There's something not right here.
- We don't have helmet cams.
Why did it kill Rassmussen like that?
That's what they do,
isn't it? Kill people?
But that's a direct attack.
It's not how they operate. Dust grows.
Consumes the host.
They evolve. You said so yourself.
Maybe. There's something going on here.
Something we're not getting.
COMPUTER: 'Please stand clear of the pod.
'Dangerous materials in transit.'
What now? We can't stay in here.
We're going to freeze to death.
And we can't go back out there
because the Sandmen will get us.
"Sandmen"?
Yeah, it's a good name.
It fits. Like the song.
♪ Bah, bah, bah... ♪
No, you don't get to name things.
I'm the Doctor. I do the naming!
All right. Sorry.
It's like the Silurians all over again!
OK, well, what would you
prefer then? The "Dustmen"?
(Sandmen.)
- What did you just say?
- When? - 1.83 minutes ago.
I said we don't have helmet cams.
THUDDING AND GROWLING
Doctor, that door isn't
going to last much longer.
So, what do we do?
We let them in.
What?!
Hmm. Clever, that.
Clever strategy.
If they'd stayed in there,
they'd have frozen to death.
So, the Doctor had to let the
creatures in. That was his theory.
Oh, I'm not dead.
You've probably guessed that by now.
CREATURE GROWLS
CLUNKING
What happen?
Must be damage from when
we fell out of orbit.
THEY COUGH AND SPLUTTER
We have to go back.
CREATURE ROARS
I don't know what to do. I can't save us.
- 474 can. - What?! - PUNCH LANDS
CREATURE MURMURS AND GROWLS
HE MOUTHS SILENTLY
The Doctor worked it out.
The creatures... can't see.
CREATURE GROWLS
Sssh!
- CLATTERING
- Run! Engine room!
What happened?
HOARSELY: 474 help.
What?!
474... die soon.
No, no! Don't say that!
You got us through!
You can survive this!
CREATURES ROAR
Chopra go.
Get ship.
Chopra be safe.
Chopra pretty.
Yaaaargh!
You said you felt like you
were being watched, Clara.
- "Paranoia", you said.
- Not this time.
There is a feed. Wireless.
These images are being
stored by someone. Collated.
Nagata, look at this footage!
What's wrong with it?
- What's wrong with it?
- Don't know.
Look, there's one very
obvious thing about it.
Do you see it yet?
No? OK. I'll tell you what's wrong.
There's footage here of everyone.
But what's missing in all of it?
What can't you see anywhere?
Not in the footage, not on this ship.
Look...
Really look.
There are no cameras here.
No CCTV.
No helmet cams.
So, how and why does
this footage even exist?
The dust has been watching us.
Each little organic speck...
.. just a tiny spy!
Drifting through the air.
The monsters have been with us all along.
That's why the Sandmen are blind.
Their visual receptors are being
hijacked! But by whom, and why?
And then, there's this.
That's you, Clara.
That's you, looking at me.
Me?
You went into the pod.
The Morpheus process has begun.
Well...
There's nothing here from
Chopra's point of view
because he refuses to use Morpheus.
But everybody else is here. Including you.
You don't have a camera, Clara.
But you will have by now,
sleep in your eye.
OK, well, we'll fix this.
You will fix this.
Yes. I'm sure it'll be fine.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
Sure?
We will sort this, Clara.
We'll sort you. We'll sort Nagata.
And everyone back on Triton.
And then we will destroy Morpheus forever.
OK then.
Let's get on with it.
The power's been almost
entirely out since we arrived.
But we've still got emergency lighting.
But the engines are still on.
Well, there was that incident
with the grav-shields, but...
Ah! What, what, what?
The grav-shields didn't fail.
They were deliberately powered down.
By the Sandmen?
Well, that's not their style, is it?
It's like... It's like
something's been kept here.
Near the engines. Where it's hot.
Like something's being...
kept alive.
COMPUTER: 'Warning! Dangerous
materials in transit.
'Human contact not advised.
'Warning! Dangerous materials in transit.
'Human contact not advised.'
Well, you said someone's
watching. Collating images.
- Yeah. - Well, if it's not
the Sandmen, then who is it?
I have an idea who.
A very... nasty idea.
In the absence of any further
communication with Chief Nagata
and the others, I must regrettably
assume them to be deceased.
Under the circumstances, I'm
now returning to the ship
and will begin preparations
to destroy Le Verrier station.
DOORS SLIDE OPEN
GROWLING
WEAPON POWERS UP
Who's there?
Chief?!
HE WHIMPERS
GROWLING
SCREAMING
"Rescue ship"?
- Why are we going to the rescue ship?
- Because that's where he'll be.
'Gagan Rassmussen. I'm Gagan Rassmussen.
'This is Le Verrier lab
in orbit around Neptune.
'I've put things together
into some kind of order...'
You had that prepared well
in advance, didn't you?
Your statement.
Your alibi.
There would inevitably be
questions when you got to Triton.
So, you needed to get your story straight.
'This is what happened.'
CLANKING
You can't fight them, Doctor.
There's no point.
They're the future.
A new life form!
A BETTER life form.
That's very clear to me now.
They've made me understand.
And we're to be their food
and that's only correct.
I just needed to find a way
to get them off this station,
and back to Triton. And
then, they'll spread.
- Spread everywhere.
- And that's what you want?!
You're helping them wipe out Humanity?
Things have been made very clear to me!
We saw you die!
The Sandmen swallowed you...
I think the Professor has been
playing a long game. Am I right?
They speak to me...
in my mind.
Trust me, I think...
But they're like children.
Babies.
So new.
Evolving.
Hungry.
Always so hungry.
I made them understand.
We had to find a way out.
And then there'd be new food sources.
Unlimited.
So, they spared me.
And we waited.
You and your cargo?
I got it in here while
you were all distracted.
BEEPING
What's in there?
Dust?
It's like smuggling a jam jar
full of germs through customs.
No. No.
More than that.
What do you mean?
I've been working on Morpheus
for a very long time, Doctor.
I had to start somewhere.
Morpheus's first client.
Patient Zero.
The ultimate Wide-Awake.
Inside there...
is a man who hasn't slept in five years.
Or what's left of him.
He's the well-spring.
Once we get to Triton,
he will spread his spores.
But you said it was an encoded signal.
Something electronic
in the Morpheus process
that changed the chemical
reaction in the brain.
That's how it started, yes.
But it's changing all the time.
Evolving new ways to infect.
To flourish.
Whole moons, whole planets,
whole civilisations.
They'll spread everywhere.
You know I can't allow that.
You can't stop them.
- None of us can.
- GUN CLACKS
- WEAPON POWERS UP
- I wouldn't bet on that, pet.
BEEPING
GROWLING
BLASTER SHOTS
Doctor!
What he wants is to get
that thing off this ship.
- We have to stop him.
- Any ideas?
The doors are not a problem.
[But that is!]
We need a distraction.
When I say "run", run.
GROWLING
Hey! Sandy!
- ♪ Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom... ♪
- Run!
♪ Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom
♪ Mr Sandman, bring me your dreams... ♪
Rassmussen!
Turn off the engines. Shut this ship down!
I can't do that, I'm afraid, Doctor.
We can't fight the inevitable.
Humanity's day is done.
Yeah? Well, Humanity might have
something to say about that, pet.
- GUNSHOT
- Aargh! - No!
HE GROANS
- Is that your answer for everything?!
- Did you have a better one?
He's not the only one dead.
According to this data, we're the
only ones left alive on this station.
GROWLING AND THUDDING
Doctor...
Come on, man! We've got to go!
- This doesn't make any sense.
- What?
A man who hasn't slept for five years...
Well, you heard what he said.
That's the first Morpheus patient!
But the dust consumes the host.
And then they make
Sandmen, they conglomerate.
We escaped from that cold storage
room because they were blind.
And why power down the
grav-shields when he did?
It's like this is all for effect...
Look, can we maybe have this conversation
when we get off this thing?
.. like a story.
Come on!
THUDDING AND GROWLING
- How do we get off this crate?
- Alternative transport.
We have to get to Triton. Destroy
all the Morpheus machines.
- End this.
- This is how we get home?
I've never been so pleased to see...
CREATURES GROWL
Nagata!
Doctor, quickly!
HE MURMURS
BEEPING
- What did you just do?
- Self-destructed the grav-shields.
- What?!
- Urgh!
THEY GRUNT
It's working!
Neptune's gravity is pulling
them apart, bit by bit!
Doesn't make sense.
None of this makes any sense.
Hello again!
Thing is, you see, this
message, this testament,
it wasn't just my alibi. It was my plan.
There are no spores. No infection.
The Morpheus process remains the same.
An electronic signal that affects
the sleep centres of the brain.
Changes them.
An electronic signal that's
contained in this recording.
There it is.
Tickles, doesn't it?
I've just got time to fit this bit
in and then I can finish the story.
Then I'm going to transmit this
footage to the whole Solar System.
I do hope you've enjoyed the show.
I did try to make it exciting.
All those scary bits.
All those death-defying scrapes,
monsters, and a proper climax
with a really big one at the end!
Compulsive viewing.
I did tell you not to watch.
VOICE DISTORTS: There's nothing
left of Rassmussen any more.
Only us.
You will show this film
to your family, won't you?
And your friends.
And everyone, really.
Then we can all be together,
dust to dust.
Excuse me,
you've got something...
there...
.. just in the corner of your eye.
FADING LAUGHTER
Rigsy! Hey, what's wrong?
So, I have this, er... It
kinda looks like a tattoo.
- There's no nice way to say
you're about to die. - What?!
I don't know who did this to you,
but I do almost certainly
know how to find them.
So, this is your life, then,
bouncing around time saving people?
There have always been rumours,
mutterings about hidden streets.
Secret pockets of alien
life, right here on Earth.
Peace on this street depends on one thing.
To break it is to face the Raven.